Aitor Ledesma Villaitodo

Front End Developer

aitorlevi@gmail.com

+610419463794

Sydney, AU

/aitor-ledesma

/aitorlevi

aitorlevi.dev

I'm an experienced Front End Developer with more than 5 years of working in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. I'm good at creating websites that look nice and work well on different devices. I know about the latest ways of building websites and using front-end tools. I want a challenging job as a Front End Developer where I can use my skills to make websites that people like to use. I like working with a team and learning new things. Right now, I'm in Australia with a Work and Holidays Visa.

WORK EXPERIENCE

CGI Consultancy - Front End Developer

2021 - 2023 Barcelona, ES

- Developed and maintained a responsive web application using Oracle JET, serving 1500 employees in the sales sector. Ensured optimal user experience and adherence to industry best practices.
- Conducted unit testing and debugging to achieve 100% success in each component, ensuring seamless functionality and high user satisfaction.
- Make the application intuitive by improving certain processes, improving service calls. This change increased the usability of the application by 25%.
- Joined a cross-functional team of 15 people, including back-end developers, project managers and designers, to implement custom screens using Agile methodology.
- Mentored 2 new junior front-end developers on team in expanding JavaScript, React, and Oracle JET skillset.

Avanttic Consulting - Front End Developer

2019 - 2021 Barcelona, ES

- Led pet food brand's migration to Oracle Cloud, enhancing performance, features, and accessibility by 40%.
- Developed a law firm's website, increasing conversion rates by 50%, ensuring legal compliance, data protection, and user trust.
- Managed and developed new features for Android/iOS shopping app, increasing downloads by 60% and conversion rates by 25%.

Ogilvy One - Front End Developer

2016 - 2019 Barcelona, ES

- Creating eye-catching banners and emails for client brands, making them look good and work on most browsers and devices. The average number of hits per mailing was 5000 people with variations.
- Led the management and updating of the contents of a website with a daily traffic of 1000 users through content management systems (CMS), ensuring correct viewing from different browsers.
- Used Adobe Experience Manager to notify 1500 employees via mobile apps, enhancing user experience and employee engagement.
- Managed of landing page campaigns for applications using the MOOCA platform, made pages that attracted users and increased conversion rates to a 35%.

EDUCATION

UOC - Bachelor of Science, Engineering Technology

2022 - current Barcelona, ES

INS La Ferreria - Higher Education, Developement of Cross-Platform Applications

September 2015 - June 2016 Barcelona, ES

INS La Ferreria - Higher Education, Network Computer System Administration

September 2013 - June 2015 Barcelona, ES

TOOLKIT

- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- React
- Oracle JET